想在此处添加您的广告信息？立即联系 www.OpenSubtitles.org
早上好
Good Morning, New York.
太阳出来前，我们来谈谈奶酪
Today we aretalking about cheese until the sun comes up.
具体说，法国奶酪
Specifically,bouchon cheese.
我很喜欢跟77年的白索维农酒一起享用
I like to pair this with a nice '77 sauvignon blanc.
用来举办个大型聚会，再合适不过了
It's perfect for an intimate meal or for a large gathering.
软软的奶酪怎么会有人不喜欢？
You will never go wrong with semi-soft cheeses.
让我们去见见Crown Heights的Scott
Let us go to Scott in Crown Heights.
他一直在研究法国的布里奶酪
He has been wondering about Brie.
NASDAQ 已经放手不去
NASDAQ dropped its noisy effort
接管纽约的证券交易所了
to take over the New York Stock Exchange.
据小道消息说
It slunk away saying it became clear
这俩家公司的合并案
regulators wouldn't approve a merger
不会被通过
of the US's two dominant stock exchanges.
在纽约的Bronx的Barbara
I think we have Barbara in the Bronx.
有个关于英国奶酪的问题
She's got a question about cheddar.
说吧，Barbara
Go ahead, Barbara.
你可以吃掉我的 车，但是当心
You can have my rook,
but I will take
这个
that.
哈
Boom.
看上去调查员已经开始介入了
It seems investors may be in for an equally wild ride.
- 把那辆车拿回来 - 快点，赶紧卸完
- Get that bike around back.
- Come on, empty the truck.
嘿，是你这家伙 - 嘿
Hey, it's the man in the suit.
Hey.
你在我的地盘搞什么飞机？
What are you doing walking on my
side of the street?
真有趣
Very funny.
2B青年的应该走那边！
Punk-ass bitches walk on the other
side of the street.
昨天说过了
Same jokes as yesterday.
再让我看见你走这边，PP给你打烂
Walk by me again and I'm going to
whoop your ass.
早上好，Shaw 先生
你看上去不错嘛
Good morning, Mr. Shaw.
You are looking lean and mean today.
你真可爱，Lester
This is why I love you, Lester.
纽约真不能少了你这张俏嘴
You're the best liar in New York.
早上好，Shaw 先生  好
Morning, Mr. Shaw.
Hiya.
你的晚会准备好了
Everything is set for your dinner party.
我刚弄了些奶酪和77年的白索维农酒
I'm sending up some bouchon paired
with a '77 sauvignon blanc.
很好
Very nice.
我想确认下，你确定你要
If you don't mind my saying, are you sure you want
邀请秘书Lowe 和 Janet Ramsey来么？
Secretary Lowe and Janet Ramsey
at the party together?
看第6页有备注
They were mentioned again on Page Six.
天，我差点忘了，这俩人还是算了
Jesus! I totally forgot they were screwing.
- 恩  - 干得好 Josh
Yeah.
Nice save, Josh.
如果没有了你，那我该怎么活？
What the hell would I do without you?
你应该亲自看看招贴上怎么写的
You would have to read the Post yourself.
我是认真的。
No, I'm serious.
我快要退休了
I am kicking the tires on a couple deals.
我打算在伦敦买个酒店
I might buy a hotel in Saint Bart's.
但我需要一个 总管
I'm looking for a GM.
不知道你意下如何？
I'm going to try and steal you away.
如果我能带上Lester，就行
If I could bring Lester, we might have a deal.
好吧，没问题
Okay, deal.
好吧， 慢走
All right.
Have a good one.
Josh，还有件事
Josh, one more thing.
什么事？先生
What is that, sir?
将军
Checkmate.
有什么安全问题？
You got a security report for me?
没什么事，K先生，一个车响了，2个流浪汉和一条狗
Not much, Mr. K.
A car alarm, two homeless and a really loud dog.
- 早上好 - 嘿，Rose
- Good morning, Josh.
- Hey, Rose.
周末过的怎么样？
How was your weekend?
还好，我在这里跟他们把车库清理了一下
Good. I was here.
We steam-cleaned the garage,
灭了几个Punjab的坏蛋
had some killer take-out
from Punjab Palace.
- 你真猛 - 没错
You are a wild man.
That's me.
Mr. K.
Hey, Odessa.
我的签证要到期了，你得给我找个老公
My work visa's about to expire.
You must find me a husband.
好的，面包圈在哪呢？
Okay. Can I have my bagel first?
我得找个男人，以免被这帮家伙扔出国。
I need a man before these pricks throw me
out of the country.
- 好，Manuel怎么样？ 他挺帅
All right,and what about Manuel?
He's a catch.
- 我试了 - 他受不鸟我
I tried.He couldn't handle me.
好吧， Rose，这段别写
Okay. Rose,don't write that down.
- 早 - 早，Kwan
- Morning. - Morning, Kwan.
3714 和 4399 有人过生日
We have birthdays in 3714 and 4399.
Jameson兄弟喜欢木兰花的杯子蛋糕
The Jameson twins like the cupcakes from Magnolia,
Causwell先生喜欢巧克力冰激凌
Mr. Causwell likes the hot fudge sundae at Sardi's.
Hightower女生3天前飞抵了开罗
And Mrs. Hightower landed three days early
马上就到到了
from Cairo,be here in an hour.
她知道？
Does Mr. Hightower know?
Josh，来下，有事
Josh, a word,right now.
马上，Simon 先生
Yes, sir, Mr. Simon.
Charlie跑哪了？看门的地方空无一人
Where's Charlie? I got an empty concierge desk.
他可能在 Cronan 女士那里
I think he's checking on Mrs. Cronan.
扯蛋，Cronan女士在接受治疗
Now that's bullshit!
Mrs. Cronan is at physical therapy.
3分钟，我要见人
He has got three minutes.
...仅在原告证明...
...can only be convicted if the prosecution
proves all the...
Miss lovenko.
妈呀，啥？
Holy shit! What?
有件事，需要你帮个忙
We do this thing,you and I,
你装作没有在准备考试
where you pretend not to study
for the bar exam
而我假装没看见
and I pretend not to notice.
神马？先生？
I'm sorry, I don't know what you're
talking about, sir.
瞧，这就上手了 - 啥？
See, we're doing it.
Doing what?
现在，我们在做你装作没在...
Right now,
we're doing the thing,where you pretend not...
啥
No.
我知道考试临近了，去我办公室学吧
I know the exam is coming up this week,
so study in my office
在午饭的时候？ 尽管我也没去过
during your lunch break, okay?
Because I never use it.
恩，但我没在学，那你是神马意思？
Okay, but I'm not studying,
so it would not make much sense.
慢，嘘，听见没？
Wait. Shh! Hear that?
什么在响
Someone is buzzing.
嘿，嘘
Hey, shush!
每个人，安静
Everybody, shush!
谁在嗡嗡？
Who's buzzing?
我听见了，虽然很小
I hear it.It's faint,
我知道你盖着，但我听见了，坦白吧
it's muffled,but I hear it.
Fess up!
谁在嗡嗡，快说
Who's buzzing?
Come on!
谁丫的在嗡嗡？
Who the hell is buzzing?
是我，对不起，我开了震动。
It's me, my bad.
I had it on vibrate.
Josh，这是Enrique Dev' Reaux
Josh, this is Enrique Dev' Reaux.
他是我们的新电梯员
He's our new elevator operator.
我叫你来了吗？
I didn't hire you.
他是个印第安混血，我们需要一个
He's a quarter Cherokee,
you know we need an Indian.
给个机会吧
So give him a shot.
很高兴见到您，Kovaks先生
It's a pleasure to meet you, Mr. Kovaks.
我在BK干了3年了
I've spent the last three years
working at the BK,
而且我也准备好来着了
and I'm ready for the big leagues.
BK？虾米？ 村里的？
BK? What is that? A building downtown?
不，是时代广场的汉堡王店。
No, it's a Burger King in Times Square.
好吧，跟我走
All right.Walk with me,
Mr. Dev'Reaux.
这里的普通套房造价560万美元
The average apartment at The Tower
costs $5.6 million.
这是北美最贵的地皮
It's the most expensive real estate
in North America.
我们有最好的视野，最高端的安全系统
We have the best views,
the most advanced security system,
杂七杂八的各种安全设施
keyless entry,24-hour video
vibration detection.
你知道这些人买的是什么吗？
But you know what these people
are really buying?
白人邻居？
White neighbors?
我们，服务人员
Us. The staff.
他们买的是我们每天全身心的服务
They pay for our full and undivided attention
seven days a week.
所以这里不许有手机，手机
So there's no cell phones, iPhones,
手机，手机，还有手机
BlackBerries,texting, tweeting...
BK有个规定，不能在储藏室做爱
They had a rule at the BK,
no sex in the storage room.
跟您的无手机规定一个意思？
Same as your phone rule, right?
不一样，因为你的JJ
No, not the same,because your dick
不得不跟你来上班
has to come with you to work, Mr. Dev'Reaux,
但是你的手机可以呆在家里
but your phone can stay at home.
不要藏在你的口袋里，袜子里
So don't hide it in your pocket
or tuck it into your sock,
更不要粘在蛋蛋上，或塞在屁眼里
don't tape it under your balls
or stick it up your ass,
因为，我会找到的
because, eventually,I will find it.
BK 从来不检查我的蛋蛋
They never checked my balls at the BK.
先生，你可以叫我Enrique，"Lil' Disco"，或"嘻嘻哈哈"
Sir, you can call me "Enrique" or "Lil' Disco"
or "The Puerto Rican Mohican,"
那个是我的 嘻哈名
that's my hip-hop name.
早，Ramos 法官，怎么样？
Morning,Judge Ramos.How did you do?
Reservoir 是我的，15间房。
I ran the Reservoir,15 flat.
很棒
Nice.
Charlie跑哪了？我要抽烟
Where's Charlie?I need my cigars.
他好像带Cronan女士去做治疗了
I think he took Mrs. Cronan
to physical therapy.
我见到就会带他来的
I'll bring them up the second he gets here.
谢了
Thank you.
- 嘿，Lester - 早，Lester
- Hey, Lester.
- Good morning, Lester.
Hi, Lester.
什么东西看不到，闻起来像虫虫？
What's invisible and smells like worms?
鸟p
Bird farts.
我们已经听过了
We've heard that one before.
在学校愉快
Have a great day at school.
早，Hightower先生
Morning, Mr. Hightower.
女士
Ma'am.
先生，您在开罗的包裹3天前到了
Sir, that package you ordered from Cairo
arrived three days early.
恩，对
Hmm.Yeah.
正在从飞机场赶过来呢
It's on its way from the airport right now.
Josh，你能叫司机
Josh, can you have the chauffeur
到后门等我们会吗？
pick us up at the back, please?
已经在了，谢谢
Already done.Thank you.
亲爱的，走吧
Darling, let's go.
那人的女儿像个 花鸡
That guy's daughter looks like a prostitute.
这里禁止评论
We're all about discretion here,Mr. Dev'Reaux.
好吧，你们怎么分小费的？
Right, right.How do you guys split up the tips?
我们不收小费
We don't. We never take tips at The Tower.
我不想谈这个
No, I don't really want to talk
about it right now.
- Charlie. - Sasha!
你兄弟来了，我上班了，不能聊天
Your brother's coming,
I'm at work and I can't talk right now.
你来晚了20分钟，Ramos法官的雪茄呢？
You're 20 minutes late!
Where are Judge Ramos' cigars?
这儿
Right here.
Josh，我受够了
Josh, I'm freaking out.
有什么需要帮忙的?
Can I help you?
忙你的
Go.
什么？
What?
我们刚做了孕检，3个月了
We just went to the OB/GYN,
the baby is in the third trimester,
孩子头太大，你妹的B太紧
its head is six inches wide,
your sister has a tiny vagina.
谁都说没事，没B事？
Everyone tells me to stop worrying.
I said, "Stop worrying?"
孩子的头要被 挤了
In labor its head is going to get crushed
也可能冲破你妹的B！
or it's going to blow out your sister's vagina.
不要在这里谈 B
Don't say the "V" word in the lobby.
我给你叔Marty打电话了
I called your Uncle Marty.
他说你家族的所有女性B都紧
He said all the women in your family
have teeny tiny vaginas.
我一直帮你，整整一个星期了
I've been covering your ass all week.
Simon 一直紧抓不放
Simon is breathing down my neck.
- 你丫的在干吗？ - 我太担心了
- What are you doing? - I'm worried.
你听到我说的没？Simon要开了你
Did you hear what I was saying?
Simon is going to fire you.
他怎么会开了我？我搞到红花了
Simon is not going to fire me today.
I got the red flowers.
红花
Red flowers?
对，中国人的新年
Yeah, it's Chinese New Year.
金女士马上就到了
Mrs. Jin will be down here any second.
中国人要 拜年，要红红火火
It's crucial the first thing she hears
be something positive.
她的一年运气全搭这上了
Her entire year depends on it.
[中文]祝你新年快乐，完事如意
Mrs. Jin.
新年快乐
Happy New Year.
你看到笑容了吗？
Did you see that smile?
您要见我？
Wanted to see me?
对
Yeah.
Fitzhugh 拒绝离开
Fitzhugh is refusing to leave.
我们从未赶任何人出去
We've never had a forced eviction at The Tower.
如果他们把Fitzhugh先生和家人撵到街上
If they drag Mr. Fitzhugh
and his family into the street,
对我们很不利
it's bad for all of us.
去和他谈谈
Why don't you talk to him?
你的职责，Josh
This is your responsibility, Josh.
银行早上要来人，把他弄出去
The bank comes in the morning.
Get him out.
Fitzhugh先生，我是Josh。
Mr. Fitzhugh,it's Josh Kovaks, sir.
早啊， Josh，你一个人？
Good morning, Josh.Are you alone?
恩
Yeah.
嘿，你有没看今天股市？
Hey, did you see what the market did today?
涨了106点，问我为什么会这样
Went up 106 points.Ask me why it did that?
为什么
Why?
我也不知道，但我曾经知道
I don't know,but I used to know.
这也是为什么Merrill Lynch雇佣我的原因
That's why they hired me at Merrill Lynch.
Fitzhugh先生，您知道这房子现在归银行了吧
Mr. Fitzhugh,you know this apartment
is now owned by the bank.
他们希望您能够即刻腾出来
They'd like you to vacate immediately.
我们给我们的孩子说，我们要
We told the kids that we were turning the apartment
把这里变成公园，绿色点
into a park. Going green.
为了解释为什么卖掉家具
That's how we explained all the furniture
还有这个帐篷
being sold and the tents in the living room.
幸亏孩子们太萌，就信了
Luckily, my children aren't very bright,
so they bought it.
但是他们的朋友很精
But they have smart friends and those friends
are catching on.
先生，明天银行就要来人了
Sir, the bank will be here tomorrow morning.
20年前，我在耶鲁，现在却成了无家可归
I went to Yale 20 years ago,
and now I'm a squatter.
等不及同学聚会了，“你好，我流浪汉”
Can't wait for their reunion.
"Hello, nice to see you.I squat."
其他家里人呢？
What about family?
我花光了全部的钱，他们不接电话了
No,I invested all their money.
They won't return my calls.
我本可以睡在车里，但是3月前车被收走了
I'd sleep in my car,but they repossessed
it three months ago.
所以，我不得不呆在这
So, you see,I have to stay here,
因为我没地方可去了
because we have nowhere else to go.
你现在是钉子户，算是非法的。
It's illegal for you to be here.
You're committing a crime.
我懂
I understand that.
我们明天会维修电梯
But we might be doing some elevator
maintenance tomorrow.
所以电梯明天可能会停运
I'm thinking that the elevators
will be shut down
然后银行的人可能明天暂时来不了
and those people from the bank will just have
to come back another time.
因为，你应该去试试
Because,it's like you go down one.
Hey, Mr. Kovaks.
Shaw先生，这位是Mr. Dev'Reaux.
Mr. Shaw,I see you met Mr. Dev'Reaux.
这人拥有一座小岛和摩托艇，真酷哇
This guy owns his own island with jet skis.
How cool is that?
呃..这是我们的实习电梯员
He's our probationary elevator operator.
他还在观察期，没到面试阶段
He's still very early in the interview process.
为何不现在面试呢
Why don't we finish the job interview right now, Josh?
例如我问 给我一个汉堡包
Suppose I ask you to pick me up a cheeseburger,
你怎么回答？
Enrique,what would you say?
您想要什么风味的？
How do you like it cooked?
我只想要个法国布里奶酪
The thing is,I like a certain kind
of Brie on my burger,
但是只有乡下的Danny的奶酪店才卖
and they only sell it at Danny's Cheese Shop
downtown.
我马上去
I'm on my way.
还有牛肉不要有添加剂的
And the beef has to be grass-fed.
先生，纽约最好的屠户在Bleecker街。
The best butcher shop in New York is on
Bleecker Street, sir.
Josh，我要他
Josh, hire him.
好的，我也是这么想的
Yes, that was my gut, sir.
还有，有件事
And, Enrique,one other thing.
我想随时吃到我要求的汉堡包
I like to get my own burgers
whenever possible.
尽管在Belize（洪都拉斯），我还有自己的小岛
I may have my own private island in Belize,
但在内心，我只是个Josh这样的人
but deep down I'm just an Astoria boy like Josh here.
我们来自同一个地方
We come from the same neighborhood.
恩，就是，104号. Go Lions街
That's right,PS 104. Go Lions!
我的第一份工作是在Aqueduct赛道上扫马粪
My first real job was shoveling horseshit
at Aqueduct Racetrack.
别让我忘了这事
Don't you ever let me forget it.
不会的！
I won't, sir.
现在，去楼下，Rose那里拿些命名牌
All right, go downstairs
and get a nametag from Rose.
谢谢，先生。 谢谢
Thank you, sir.Thank you.
为何不今晚出动呢？Josh？ 搞点什么
Why don't we hit it tonight, Josh?
Raise some hell.
我们得在9小时内回来
We have to be back here in nine hours.
还记得你在时代广场酒吧跳舞时候吗？
Remember that time you danced on that bar
in Times Square?
我差点乐晕了
I almost fainted.
只是你6年前的一个醉梦而已
That's a drunken dream you had six years ago.
你在那里晃你的PP
You were shaking your ass up there
like Tina Turner.
在百老汇，半裸奔
Running half naked on Broadway
还给游客说你是狮子王里的Mustafa
telling tourists you were Mustafa
from The Lion King.
真荒唐，哪发生过
That's ridiculous.It never happened.
我本来不想告诉你，这是我任职的最后一年了。
I was waiting to tell you.
This is going to be my last year at The Tower.
神马？
What?
几个月后，我就要去圣地亚哥了
In a few months,I'm headed to San Diego
跟Lorraine过日子去了
to spend a little time with Lorraine.
我甚至会到世界各地讲各种 P笑话
I might even cruise around the world with
all the other old farts.
Wow.
真棒，真的很棒，我会想你的
That's great.That's really great.
I'm going to miss you.
我也会想你的，Josh
I'll be thinking about you, Josh.
车来了
Here's your bus.
想想你在那跳舞的样子
Be thinking about how you danced on that bar.
我全记在这了
Yeah!I got it all up here.
我不知道你从哪弄的这玩意
I don't know where you got that.
生命循环，Josh，生命循环
Circle of life, Josh. Circle of life!
虽然很少人会自己宰感恩节火鸡
Not many of you kill your own Thanksgiving turkey,
但你或许可以考虑下
but you might want to consider it.
操，Rita，赶紧死过来
Shit, Rita,get your ass back in here!
我才不会到处追你。
I ain't going to be chasing you all around.
再见，Slide
Goodbye, Slide!
嘿，Rita，现在可是大早上5点30
Hey, hey, Rita, come on now,it's 5:30 in the morning.
别闹了行不
Not little shit like this.Come on now.
我给你说了，我根本不认识个叫Maria的
I told you,I don't even know nobody named Maria.
就是就是，他咋就认识你呢？
Yeah, well,she sure as shit knows you, Slide!
那个号码肯定错了
It was a wrong number.
那他怎么知道你名字？ 为嘛？
Then why did she ask for you, stupid? Why?
肯定是打错了，只是..
It was a wrong number!I just...
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you are saying, bitch!
Lester，都15了，Shaw的车怎么还在这？
15.Why is Mr. Shaw's car still here?
他可能病了
Maybe he's sick.
那个黑车停在这2天了
That black sedan has been parked there for two days.
为什么没有拖走也没罚单？
Why no boot or ticket?
我给警察打了2次电话
I called the cops twice.
你还记得那天早上的抢劫案么
Do you remember that morning robbery
去年，在国家银行
at the International last year?
你现在把门锁上，疏散大伙
I want you to slowly lock the door
and clear the lobby.
冷静
Stay calm.
全锁好，关好门和电梯，黑色预警
Lock it down. Code Black on all
doors and elevators.
重复，黑色预警
Repeat, Code Black.
什么事黑色预警
What's Code Black?
开玩笑呢？上个月我们开会还说呢
Are you serious?
We talked about it at the meeting last month.
让我看看外面出什么事了
Let me see the outside of the building.
看样我我们要被抢劫了
I think we're about to be robbed.
4个人，带着枪
There were four guys out there with guns.
他们去哪了？
Where did they go?
我看看车库
Let me see the garage.
干洗店的人怎么在这？昨天不是洗衣日么？
Why is Stillman here?
Laundry pick-up was yesterday.
Shaw 让我们叫他来
Mr. Shaw asked us to call him.
有人把酒洒在他的桌布上了
Someone spilled wine on his tablecloth.
他马上就下来了
He's bringing it down right now.
这些人不是干洗店的伙计
Wait a second. Those are not the Stillman brothers.
他们绑架了Shaw
Oh, my God,they're taking Shaw.
这不是抢劫，这是绑架
This isn't a robbery,it's a kidnapping.
绑架，打110
It's a kidnapping!Call 911!
马上
Yes, sir.
黑色预警，Manuel
Code Black, Manuel!Code Black!
什么黑色预警？
What's Code Black?
Hey! Whoa!Whoa!
站住！
Hey! Stop!
射穿那些轮胎
Shoot at the tires!
我的是充电的！
I only have my Taser!
站住！
Hey, stop!
当心点！
Watch out!
进来 进来
- Move in! Move in!- Move in!
别动
Don't move.
举起手来
Get your hands in the air!
FBI，举起手来
FBI, show me your hands.
- 走吧 - 好了，完事了
- Let's go.- Okay, all right.
手背后！
Put them behind your back!
放松
Take it easy.
嘿，抓错人了，他是被绑架的。
No, get off him! He's the victim!
那是Arthur Shaw，住在我们那的
That's Arthur Shaw!He lives in The Tower.
他叫人洗东西，结果被绑架了
He was bringing his laundry down.They kidnapped him.
这不是绑架，这是逃逸。
This was not a kidnapping,it was an attempt to flee.
虾米？
What?
扣上他，把这人弄走
Arrest him and get him out of here.
Josh，帮个忙，把加热器关了，盖上泳池
Josh, do me a favor,turn off the heater
and cover the pool.
我不喜欢浪费钱
I hate to waste money.
华尔街的首脑Arthur Shaw
Wall Street kingpin Arthur Shaw,
福布斯富人榜上138位
number 138 on the Forbes 400 last year,
在今天逃逸过程中被拘捕
was arrested today in Manhattan while
trying to flee the city.
据说他将被控以
Sources have confirmed that he'll be charged
多项证券欺诈
with several counts of securities fraud
Shaw 的多处财产已被冻结
and an immediate asset freeze of Mr. Shaw's holdings
has been ordered.
Shaw 的律师进行的举报
Shaw's lawyers have called the arrest
另一个典型的华尔街追捕行动
"another example of the Wall Street witch-hunt,"
但是委员会的线人称这起诈骗
but sources at the SEC believe the fraud
将成为历史性的一点
in this case could be of epic proportions.
在这个国家，在判刑之前都是无罪的
In this country you're innocent until proven guilty,
所以，不管你听别人怎么说他
so no matter what you hear about Mr. Shaw
being a liar and a cheat,
或者他的生意怎么怎么样
or his entire business being some sort
of elaborate scam,
我们暂时还不清楚事情
we simply don't know the truth yet.
我还有鞋子没擦呢
I've got shoes to polish, Mr. K.
这跟我们有什么关系？
What does this got to do with us?
这6年，Shaw一直是这里的委员
For the last six years,
Mr. Shaw was on the board of The Tower.
那我们再去找个人当委员？
So we have to find a new board member?
不是
No.
几年前，在会议室
Several years ago at one of the meetings,
我们请他帮了一个忙
he was asked to do a favor for us.
他掌管了你们所有人的养老金
He was asked to manage all of your pensions.
养老金
Pensions?
是的
And he did.
虽然钱很少
He took us on even though it was
a small account.
但他同意接管了
He agreed to handle it.
谁让他这么做的？
Who asked him to do that?
我，Rose，我请求的
I did, Rose.I asked him.
那么还剩下多少钱？
Mr. K, what's left in the pension?
这事太突然，现在也没办法调查了
Kwan, all this just happened,so there's no way of knowing,
还有，这可能是个误会
and by the way,this could be a mistake.
多少钱？告诉我们
How much, Josh? Tell us.
现在，他们说
Right now, they're saying that anyone who
任何给Shaw的投资都是诈骗
invested with Mr. Shaw has been defrauded,
意思就是说，没了
and that more than likely,it's all gone.
没有养老金
There is no pension.
等下，等下，我想问
Wait, wait.Wait a minute.I'm sorry.
这是怎么回事？
How did this happen?
那人可是纽约最棒的人
The guy is the best in New York
而且他说他能让我们的投资翻3倍
and he promised he could triple our portfolio.
现在我们没钱了？
So they're going to get our money?
这家伙有上百万资产呢，对吧？
The guy had billions of dollars, right?
对，时间问题
Of course,it's just a matter of time.
所以我们只需要等待就行了吧，毕竟是我们的
So we have to stay patient and be positive,
because it has to be there.
我看新闻了
I heard on the news when they arrested Shaw
他的账户里只有600块钱
that he only had $600 in his checking account.
好吧，你们可能需要一段时间来接受事实
Look, some of you may need some time to
process this.
如果有人想回家休息
If anyone wants to go home,
我会找一些人替代你们几天
I will call in a temp crew for the rest of the day.
我想这些明天就会见分晓了
I'm sure that this will all be cleared up tomorrow.
我能问个问题吗？
Can I ask you something, Mr. K?
说吧
Yeah.
他也拿了你的钱吗？
Did he get your money, too?
是的
Yeah, Odessa.
准确的说
For the record,
我还从没让任何人让我的钱翻倍过
I never asked anyone to triple my portfolio.
但几个小时前
Just an hour ago,
一个联邦法官刚宣布了1000万的保释
a federal judge released Arthur Shaw
on $10 million bail,
但仅允许他在中央公园的居所内
on condition he remain under house arrest
at his penthouse apartment
被软禁的情况下
on Central Park West.
Shaw，请发表份声明
Mr. Shaw, I need a statement from you.
退后
You need to back off.
说句话，Shaw
Can I get a comment please, Mr. Shaw?
退后，退后
You need to back off. Excuse me.
这儿！ 这！看这里！
Here!Over here! Come on, Shaw!
Right here! Shaw!
来笑一个，茄子！
Shaw, can we get a picture?
看这里！
Over here, Mr. Shaw!
我们正带领他和他的律师回到居所
We're taking Shaw and his attorney
up to the penthouse.
我需要Shaw的个人安全代码
I need Mr. Shaw's personal security code.
24719.
这是我小时候在施坦威大道的地址
That was my street address on Steinway Boulevard
in Astoria when I was a kid.
我的客户请求进入43号锻炼馆
My client would like access to the gym on 43.
即便是杀人犯也有15分钟的锻炼时间
Even serial killers get 15 minutes
of exercise a day.
他可以随时跳窗户
He has my permission to jump out the window.
软禁的条款很简单
The rules of Mr. Shaw's house arrest are simple.
未经FBI允许，不允许任何访客
Kovaks, no visitors without prior permission
from the FBI.
任何进出的邮件都要审查
All incoming and outgoing mail gets
vetted by my office.
任何食物，包裹
All food deliveries, packages,
清扫，修理服务必须通知探员
cleaning, repairs, all that has to be cleared
by the agent on duty.
你要告诉你的员工，这里
You tell your staff that this penthouse is now
是最高安全监视区，而且会被守卫
a maximum security prison
and it will be guarded as such.
FBI将控制电梯和这层楼
The FBI is in control of the elevator
and this floor.
搞什么飞机？
What the hell is this?
1963年的法拉利250 GT Lusso,
Agent Denham,that is a 1963
Ferrari 250 GT Lusso,
曾被著名的Steve McQueen驾驶过
owned and raced by the coolest cat
who ever lived, Steve McQueen.
这曾是他的宝贝
This was his baby,
现在是我的
and now it's my baby.
你把车停在你的客厅里？
You got Steve McQueen's car
parked in your living room?
你还真是个 2B 老头
And here I thought you were an asshole.
10年前我花了1百万买到的
I paid a million for it 10 years ago.
翻10倍我也不会卖
I wouldn't sell it for 10 times that.
怎么把它搞出去？
We're 65 stories up.
How do we get it out of here?
不可能
You don't.
这车是从零件组装起来的
This car was taken apart piece by piece
就在这里
and reassembled inside this room.
这车会在拍卖会上被卖掉
This car will eventually be sold at auction
跟你其他的东西一样
with the rest of your belongings.
前提是我有罪，但是我没有
Only if I'm guilty,Agent Denham,which I'm not.
如果你未经我允许，私自离开
If you leave this apartment for any reason
without my say so,
你将会被送给联邦看管
and you'll be remanded into federal custody
而且承担1000万的保释金
and forfeit $10 million bail.
你今天心情不错嘛
You have yourself a nice day, Mr. Shaw
跟我走走吧？
Kovaks, will you come with me?
帮个忙可以吗？
Josh, do me a favor, will you?
好的
Yes, sir, Mr. Shaw
一定要亲自看好送来的食物
Make sure you handle all my food deliveries.
你还不懂，我是无罪的
You're smart enough to know I'm innocent.
I don't want the help to spit in my coffee.
They wouldn't do that, sir.
Yeah, but you
get it, right?
Do it as a favor to me.
Sorry, we don't
accept tips
at The Tower.
Right, I'm sorry.
Sometimes I forget
the rules.
Why did you let him
get away with that?
When he made that crack
about the help
spitting in his coffee.
You wanted to hurt him.
Hell, I wanted to hurt him.
Sometimes residents
say things they don't mean.
It doesn't faze me.
Either that or
you got no balls.
What?
I'm out of line.
I'm sorry.
I have balls,
all right.
I'm sure you got
big balls. Whatever.
I don't have to
defend my balls to you.
I'm just saying
the guy stole from everyone
who works in your building
and it looked like you
gave him a free pass.
Maybe next time I'll
rip out his larynx,
but today I chose to
do my job as manager
of this building.
Okay, my mistake, Kovaks.
Just that most
guys from your block
in Astoria
can't control
themselves.
And most girls
from Forest Hills
don't end up in the FBI.
That's where
you're from, right?
Here.
This is where most
white-collar crimes
are solved, the garbage.
When do you think
you will be getting
the money back?
I'm not really
allowed to discuss
the case with you.
But you're allowed
to clothesline me?
I was apprehending
a fugitive.
He's only a fugitive
if he's guilty, right?
Oh!
Aren't you
the loyal friend?
I never said
we were friends.
You play chess together,
you're the one
who asked him to
invest the pension.
I get his mail,
I open his car door,
I buy his cheese.
We're not friends.
Let me ask you something,
Kovaks.
If he's innocent,
where's the money?
How should I know?
The same way you knew
I was from Forest Hills.
You pay attention.
I just want to know
what I'm supposed
to tell my staff.
Is that too much to ask?
Tell them he's guilty.
Get on the car!
Hey! Hey, hey!
Come on,
put your hands
behind your back!
Come on, man,
what's this about?
This is bullshit! Shit!
That's police brutality, yo!
Come on now.
Man in the suit,
you seeing this shit?
You're my witness.
Take a cell phone picture.
Take a picture, man.
No, my cell phone
doesn't have a camera.
If you see Rita,
tell her I said
to call her brother.
Rita?
Yeah, her brother's
a bail bondsman.
Tell her I said
to use that money
I gave her to get
her teeth fixed.
Come on now,
what you got to be
pushing me like that?
Ladies and gentlemen,
the next Brooklyn bound
local train is now arriving.
Please step away
from the platform edge,
especially when
trains are entering
and leaving the station.
Hello.
Dr. Carr, dial 118, please.
Hey, what happened?
Lester tried to step
in front of
a subway train tonight.
An off-duty
traffic cop was there
and pulled him back
at the last second.
They have him on
a 48-hour hold.
Where is he?
If you wanted a sick day,
all you had to do was ask.
Seriously,
I need you
back at work.
I'm going to
tell the doctor
somebody pushed you.
It was a misunderstanding,
okay?
I gave it to him, Josh.
All my money.
I asked him to
invest it for me.
Shaw?
Yeah.
A couple of months ago,
I gave him everything I had,
my life savings.
Six years
working the back door
at the Waldorf,
nine at the Carlyle,
three at the Pierre,
11 with you at The Tower.
That's 29 years
of opening doors.
$73,000 and change,
and I gave him every penny.
In a few months
I won't have
money for rent.
I can't retire now.
All those years
of opening doors,
year after year.
Truth is, people can
open their own doors.
Not the way you do it.
Lester, he's going
to pay you back
every penny.
I promise.
Josh, please calm down.
Hold the elevator.
You can't go up there.
You're acting
like a vigilante.
Move your hand.
I won't move my hand.
Move your hand!
Relax. You're not
using your head.
- Hey, Charlie.
- Hey, Josh.
Hey.
So, they're
evicting me
this morning.
My wife already
took the kids,
wants a divorce.
So, if you need me,
I'll be living in this box.
Can I ask you a question?
You're a Wall Street guy.
When did Shaw realize
that it was over for him?
Ten months,
maybe a year.
I heard he was
interviewing lawyers
over the summer.
So if he took
someone's money
a few months ago?
Probably needed the cash
to keep up appearances.
Throw his famous
Labor Day party
at the beach.
At a certain point,
it isn't about
securities fraud,
it's about catering.
Drop Mr. Fitzhugh on 59.
I'm going to the penthouse.
Wow! This is
going to be good.
Don't get up.
Whoa! Where do you
think you're going?
We're just going
to get the trash.
And the breakfast order.
Go ahead.
Takes a village.
Good morning,
Josh, Charlie, Enrique.
How are you doing?
How was your Labor
Day party this year,
Mr. Shaw?
Must have been something, huh?
What did you serve? Crab legs?
Surf and turf?
I've always tried
to extend you
a certain courtesy,
but this tone
you're using...
What tone? Who gives
a shit about my tone?
What are you,
some kind of
tone master?
Josh, come on.
I'm going to ask
you one time, okay?
So you better
think really hard.
Why did you take
Lester's money?
He came to me,
he asked me to invest
and I did. It was a favor.
Mm-hmm.
$73,000? A favor?
Everything he had.
Did Lester ask you
to come up here?
Mr. Shaw,
a few hours ago,
Lester stepped
in front of a subway train.
Oh, Jesus.
- Here we go.
- What are you doing?
Josh,
you need to listen to me.
The FBI is lying to you.
Josh, put down the club.
Christ's sake,
don't do anything
you can't undo.
Investing money is a gamble.
It doesn't always pay off.
Mr. Shaw, do you care?
Josh, come on.
No, really.
Do you feel any
responsibility for what
happened to Lester?
Of course I feel badly.
I had no idea
he was going to
lose everything.
Lester has been
a part of my life
for over a decade.
Then why haven't you
asked me whether
he's alive or dead?
Josh, this car
is irreplaceable!
Not like doormen!
They make new ones
of those all the time.
Must be 50 new doormen
coming off the line
in Michigan right now!
God damn it! Stop it!
Want some Brie
with your burger?
Here you go.
Josh, don't!
Shh!
Want me to come
work for you, huh?
Want to steal
me away to
Saint Bart's?
Come on, let's go!
I'm ready to rock!
Mr. Kovaks, let me have
a swing at that shit!
No! Nobody touches
this car but me.
You think Steve McQueen
is the coolest cat
that ever lived?
Guess what?
Today, Steve McQueen
is my little bitch.
Ooh!
Ah!
Oh!
Whoops.
Don't worry,
I'll have the help
come clean that up.
Let's go.
Josh, aren't you
forgetting something?
My breakfast order.
Do you understand
the shit-storm
that can be brought
down on this building?
Shaw's lawyer will
shove harassment,
destruction of property
and civil rights charges
right down our throats!
Now, I don't care
what Shaw did
or how much money
he's accused of stealing.
And you know damn well
I got murdered by that
son of a bitch!
But a line has been crossed,
and a gang of vigilantes
will not be tolerated
at The Tower.
You're all fired.
Hey, wait, hold on.
Mr. Simon, they had
nothing to do with this.
They just
followed me up there.
I don't give a shit!
Mr. Simon, wait a minute,
my wife is eight
months pregnant.
You should have
thought of that before you
walked in that apartment.
We went up there
for Lester!
Lester's job is
waiting for him
when he gets out.
Meanwhile, the rest of you,
I want you out of
the building right now.
Um, the carpet cleaners
are coming tomorrow,
they start on 44. Okay?
Bye, Joshie.
Good luck with the bar.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
All right.
Let's go, everyone.
Back to work, okay?
Hey, Charlie, wait!
Wait. I'll call Sasha,
all right.
I'll tell her you
tried to stop me.
Please,
don't do me any favors.
And, Josh,
don't pretend to care now,
I know you always
wanted to fire me.
That's because you
stink at this job.
So I stink? I stink?
Yeah.
The guy who made Mrs. Jin
smile on Chinese New Year?
Mrs. Jin is Korean.
She's what?
That's why she was smiling.
She's not Chinese,
she's Korean.
And you believed her?
Yeah, she's Korean.
All right, Josh,
maybe she's Korean.
Why are you whispering?
She is Korean.
What's important is
that she appreciated
the gesture I made,
and that's more
than I can say
for some people.
Thanks for getting me fired.
Hey.
Hey. Thank you
for coming down.
Yeah, no problem.
You got something
for me?
Yeah. I probably
shouldn't even be
doing this,
because it violates
everything I believe in,
but I have to
get my employees'
money back, so...
This is Shaw's
travel schedule
for the last 10 years.
It's his guest registry.
Names of judges, politicians,
women,
tail number of his plane,
hull identification
number of his yacht,
names of his race horses
in West Virginia...
Gill's Pride
and Sunny Day.
Yeah, we have
all that, Kovaks.
And eventually
they're gonna sell his
planes and his yachts,
and his horses,
and the bank is
going to take it all.
You guys were his
smallest account.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Thought I'd give it a shot.
Kovaks,
you wanna get drunk?
Thanks.
I've got to be
honest with you, Kovaks.
The last time
I drank this much at a bar
I made out with a fireman.
Really?
How long ago was that?
Tuesday.
You know,
you surprise me.
I saw the security tape
of you beating the shit
out of Shaw's car.
That was badass.
Yeah, well,
badass is my middle name.
Nope. Your middle
name is Marvin.
I know that from
your file. Marvin.
All right.
That's my dead grandfather
you're laughing at.
What else is in my file?
Oh.
I know the year your
parents got divorced.
Your SAT scores.
You don't know
my SAT scores.
540, math.
480, verbal.
I retook those.
Your scores went down.
I have to
tell you something,
and I really shouldn't
be telling you this,
because it violates
everything I believe in.
Mmm-hmm.
We still haven't
found Shaw's safety net.
All these guys,
they keep some cash close by
in case they have to run.
Shaw clears out
all of his accounts
three months ago,
20 million and change.
But when we bust him,
the money isn't on him.
Wait.
$20 million?
There's a chance we'll
get lucky and find it.
And if we get lucky,
maybe you can get lucky.
I'm not lucky.
You just have
to be patient.
I don't really have
time to be patient.
Well, if you're
tired of waiting around,
you can always try
the old-school approach.
What's that?
Grab some pitchforks
and a couple of guys
and storm the castle.
They'd never
see you coming.
I have to pee.
Ooh! I'm gonna...
I have to go.
Whoa, whoa.
You can't drive.
I'm gonna get a crab.
Crab?
Listen, you violated
three federal laws
when you beat up
Shaw's Ferrari.
So what?
So a lot of guys
down at the bureau
want to buy you a drink,
and so do I.
Bye.
Goodbye.
Manuel.
Sorry, Mr. K,
I can't let you
into the building.
No, no, I just have to
grab some stuff out of
my office, okay?
I promise
I won't attack anyone.
I can't do it.
Or should I tell
Mr. Simon about you
and the cougar in 2813?
Two minutes.
Okay.
Hi,
welcome to Shake Shack.
What can I get you?
Hey, Mr. Kovaks.
Welcome to Shake Shack.
What's shaking?
We shake all day.
You like working here?
I cry at night.
You said you know
electrical engineering?
I'm on the phone
with the police.
They have a cruiser
in the area. Go away!
It's me, Mr. Fitzhugh.
Can you open the door,
please?
Hey.
Why are you
staying in this motel?
I'm thinking
of becoming
a male prostitute.
I think I might
have a better idea.
Sasha told me
you took a job.
Oh, yeah. I'm using
all the skills you
taught me as a concierge.
Thank you very much.
Hey, no spitting,
blue shirt.
Suck it,
douche bag!
It's not a bad job.
Only problem is
I need 40 hours to
get on the insurance,
it's hard to get shifts,
but if I don't get
on the insurance,
it's probably
gonna end up
costing us
around $20,000
to have the baby.
So we'll probably
have to sell it.
I need your help.
So you're saying you
wanna rob $20 million
from Arthur Shaw.
Which you think
he's hidden in
a secret wall safe
inside his
penthouse apartment.
An apartment
which he's not
allowed to leave
and is guarded by
three FBI agents,
24 hours a day.
Two.
And you wanna
do all of this
in a building
with the most
advanced security
and surveillance
system in the world.
A building which we've
all been barred from
ever entering again?
Yes. How do you
guys feel about that?
Well, I've really
enjoyed myself.
Thanks for the crackers.
Mr. Fitzhugh,
I know the money
is in that safe.
How do you know?
Because in 2003,
Shaw remodeled.
He spent like 10 million
to blow out the kitchen,
move the living room.
He even brought in
some guy from China
to do a whole
feng shui thing.
But he left
one wall standing,
dead center
in the middle
of the apartment.
That's where
he put the safe.
Maybe it's
a load-bearing wall.
No. No, it isn't.
We have the same
wall in my place.
We took it down
when we first moved in.
The FBI can't find
the money, because
he hid it in the wall.
I know it!
So you guys
in or out?
Mr. Fitzhugh?
Come back to me.
Mr. Dev'Reaux?
You know how many weeks
I'd have to work at the BK
to make 20 million?
18,600.
Charlie, come on.
Look at us.
We're basically waiters.
That's what we do.
We bring people stuff.
We don't take things.
You and I know
the movements
of every person.
We know the schedules,
deliveries and codes
for every door
and window.
We've been casing the place
for over a decade,
we just didn't know it.
We didn't know it,
because we weren't
doing it.
But we were.
No.
Okay, where do
the Lippmans keep
their passports?
In the freezer.
Mmm-hmm.
How many in
vitro fertilizations
did Miss Hansen have
before she gave
birth to Jonah?
Six.
See? We know everything!
What's the pass code
for Mr. Shaw's elevator?
I just press
the PH button.
Come on, man.
I need you.
Yeah, you need me,
because you've
got these idiots.
You think we're
getting our money back?
You think Lester is
getting his money?
I talked to the FBI.
It's gone!
So all this is
about getting it
back for Lester?
Yes! And Rose and
Miss lovenko and Manuel
and you, you jerk!
Come on! Let's storm
the castle together.
Oh, like when they went
after Frankenstein?
No, it's a different
kind of storming.
It's a storming
where the peasants
take everything back.
From like
the feudal lords and...
I'm in.
Holy shit! I'm in.
Well, now we're
undefeatable,
aren't we?
Josh, we're not criminals.
We don't know how to steal.
It's okay,
I know someone who does.
Crack four!
You must have been saying
your prayers, Slide.
You made bail.
Slide.
Thought you might
need a ride.
I haven't driven
my Nova for a few months.
Did you know that
in Spanish "No va"
means "It doesn't go"?
That's why they
didn't sell many
in Latin America.
I didn't realize Rikers
was on an actual island.
I thought
it was more of a...
I don't know, like a...
You know,
like the way Puget Sound
is actually an inlet.
But they...
You hungry?
Can I buy you some lunch?
Slide, what are you doing?
Tell me why
you bailed me out!
Take your foot
off the gas!
Answer the goddamn
question first!
Slide!
Red light!
All right,
what's going on?
You wearing
a wire or something?
Some kind of police
undercover shit?
No, I'm not a cop!
Then you brought me
out here for some
kind of freak shit, huh?
You want to
stimulate my nut sack.
Is that what it is, punk?
No! Jesus!
Then what the hell
we doing out here, man?
I don't even know your name.
I'm Josh Kovaks.
Man in the suit.
We talk almost
every morning.
How come you
bailed me out, man?
I need help with something,
and I thought
given our relationship
you might be
willing to help.
Relationship?
I ain't got no
relationship with your ass!
Our history!
What history?
I see you walking by
every now and then.
I say, "Hey, what's up,
little biatch?"
Just another
passer-by going by.
nigger walking by.
You don't remember 1971?
Mrs. Saltzburg?
We used to get dropped off
at her apartment every
morning for day care.
In 1971 I'm six!
How am I supposed to
remember some shit?
Come on, Darnell,
Mrs. Saltzburg!
Heavy-set German woman,
short goatee.
Man, you call me
Darnell one more time,
I will beat you to death.
You don't remember
Inch High, Private Eye?
Davey and Goliath?
Remember Witchiepoo?
H.R. Pufnstuf.
You got freaked
out by her?
Remember that
kid came over
and he stole my inhaler
and I couldn't breathe?
I do remember you!
You the little seizure boy
that was having them
seizures all the time!
No, I never had
any seizures!
They were minor
spasms of the throat.
And I remember
you would start
foaming up at the mouth
and your eyes
would go crooked.
It was very scary!
There was no foaming.
That was you!
A lot of people
have asthma
when they're kids.
It's not a big deal.
I outgrew it.
No. Seizure Boy.
You'd be on the floor
rolling all around.
You was having seizures!
Asthma doesn't cause
seizures, all right?
Oh, really? Then how come
nobody wanted to play
with your ass?
Nobody wanted to
have naptime with you,
nobody wanted to
do coloring with you
or nothing.
Because of your
little seizures
and didn't nobody
want to catch that shit!
I'm gonna ask you
one more time, punk.
Why did you bail me out?
Because I have a job
and I thought that
given your skill set
maybe you could
help us out.
What kind of
skill set is that?
Taking things that
don't necessarily
belong to you.
Oh, little Seizure Boy
want to try to
rob somebody, huh?
What you trying to steal?
$20 million.
Let's go get
something to eat.
Hey, guys,
this is my friend Slide.
You kidding, right?
These ain't the guys
you wanna try to
do this job with.
Yes, this is
Charlie and Dev'Reaux
and Mr. Fitzhugh.
This is a joke, right?
This guy is
the big time criminal?
Hey, what you say?
All right, guys,
take it easy.
He's totally qualified.
He's been arrested
a bunch of times,
he pays no income taxes,
he's got two
Doberman pinschers.
So let's show
him some respect.
So now we're like
The Doberman Gang?
Like the what?
It was a movie.
They trained Dobermans
to knock off a bank.
Is that the one
where Gregory Peck
was attacked by those dogs?
No, that's Boys from Brazil
with the cloned Hitlers.
Oh, shit. You guys ever
seen Boys Don't Cry?
When Hilary Swank
plays that dude.
That scared
the shit out of me.
Wait, Slide.
Sit down and talk
with us for a second.
These guys ain't
got what it take.
I can look in
their eyes and see it.
First sign of trouble,
they're gonna be
shitting in their pants.
They will not.
You don't know them.
You want me to prove it?
All right,
listen up,
y'all got 15 minutes
to go out there and
steal me something.
What do you mean?
You heard what I said.
In this mall, right now,
each one of y'all
go out there and
individually steal
$50 worth of merchandise,
come back and put
it on the table.
Then we'll talk.
Okay, 50 bucks,
no problem. Come on.
Can I go with you, Josh?
No, you ain't
going with Josh,
you go by yourself.
Everybody
going by theirself.
Anybody can't
handle this, is out.
Okay. Guys,
we can do this.
It's just shoplifting.
You got 15 minutes,
let's go.
And put your wallets
on the table. I don't
want nobody cheating.
I don't want y'all
to go buy the shit
and say you stole it.
All right, come on,
let's go.
This is a part
of our Sexy Little
Things collection.
Oh, yeah, that's great.
Love that. Yeah.
Would you like me to
ring that up for you?
No, I think I'll just
live with it a little first.
These are very
pretty Bella earrings.
They're from our
Timeless Collection.
Do you have any studs?
Yes, several.
Right here.
Do you have any hoops?
Sir, all of our earrings
are on this display.
Do you have a catalog?
Uh...
I might have
one in the back,
let me check.
How do those feel?
They feel a little tight.
Do you have them
in a half size up?
Yeah, let me
check the back.
Hey, them two
pairs of drawers
don't cost no $50.
$12 scented candle.
Okay, we'll get
to work tomorrow.
Wait a minute.
We all just
proved ourselves.
How do we know you can
really pull this off?
You each stole
$50 worth of shit,
I stole $264 in cash.
Rule number one,
never give your
wallet to a thief.
Later, bitches.
What are we
doing up here, man?
My balls are snow cones.
Can I get my jacket?
Everybody
shut up, right now.
In a robbery,
things can change quickly.
It can go from
hot to cold,
just like that.
You have to be
ready to adapt
to the situation.
You have to be able
to think on your feet.
I was on a job a few
days ago where my homie
got shot in the face.
He's kidding, right?
Get shot in the head,
it's over.
If you get shot in
your head, it's over.
If you get shot in your face,
the bullet will
go in your cheek,
then come out the other side.
Then what you
gonna do, sissy?
Die. I'm gonna die.
I saw a television show once
about a guy who
got shot in the head
with a nail gun.
He couldn't even remember
how to chew anymore.
He had to put
everything in a blender.
Yo, he couldn't
figure out how to chew,
but he could
operate a Cuisinart?
I don't think he
operated it himself.
All right,
could we just focus, please?
It's 16 degrees!
That's right!
Let's focus!
Now, earlier today
I taught you all
how to pick a lock
with a bobby pin.
I want y'all to
practice on this door.
I've got bobby pins
for all of y'all.
Here's your bobby pin.
This is your bobby pin.
This is your punk-ass
bobby pin. Take it!
You unlock the door,
you won't freeze to death.
I'm gonna be inside
having sex with Rita.
Who's Rita?
To get in the building,
we have to avoid
seven exterior cameras
and six doormen who work
at two entrance points
in rotating shifts.
Once inside,
we'll be faced with
four security officers,
who monitor a bank of
12 internal cameras,
as well as two
floating security guards,
who vary
the patrol route each day.
If we make it
through all of that,
we still have to get
through this gauntlet
of employees to
get to the elevators.
Questions?
Yeah. Who's that
girl in the red dress?
She got
the kind of titties
I like to play with.
That's Mary-Ann
from sales.
She's a lesbian.
Okay, that's irrelevant.
Mary-Ann
is a lesbian?
She was married
when she sold me
my unit.
She makes lesbian sex
with Lynn Rutherford
from accounting.
Okay...
Lynn is a lesbian?
Wait, I'm lost.
How many lesbians total
do we have to avoid?
None. We're not
avoiding lesbians.
I don't avoid
lesbians at all.
I seek lesbians out.
Lesbians got
the nicest titties.
Straight women,
they have guys
pulling and yanking on them
and sweating on them.
Lesbians get
touched delicately
by other lesbians.
It's nice.
Did anybody take in
what I just said?
Well, it seems like
there's a gauntlet
of lesbians.
No. The...
All right,
I'm just gonna keep going.
1:27,
NYPD makes third pass
in front of the building.
The parking
enforcement officer
only works the west
side of the street.
She got
a fat ass, too.
All right, baby,
I'll call you
after lunch.
I'm in a restaurant
with Josh
and a couple of other guys
across from The Tower.
Yeah. I love you.
What are you doing?
It's supposed
to be a secret.
I can't tell my wife
I'm having a lunch?
We're not having lunch.
We're casing the front
of the building.
Now they can trace
our steps back to us.
I didn't tell her what
restaurant we were at.
You said,
"The restaurant
across from The Tower."
I didn't say
which restaurant
across from The Tower.
Geez, a hamburger's $24.
We can't afford
to eat here anyway.
Hey, we can order
whatever we like,
because
Lunch is on me.
This is the main
electrical room.
You can override
the elevators from here
or shut them down completely.
Mr. Dev'Reaux,
who took some courses
at DeVry Technical Institute,
is gonna be our
point man on this.
Online.
What?
I went there to
go get my master's
in electronics,
but somebody said,
"You got to go
to college first."
I was, like,
"Yeah, it wasn't
in the brochure."
Okay,
but you understand what...
Absolutely.
I weld stuff and I'm,
like, you flip it on and off.
It's all about power.
Hey, man, how is this
supposed to be right
if you made it out of Legos?
Well, the dimensions
are completely accurate.
Yeah, who's this
little nigglet? Webster?
Man, you might as
well use Lincoln Logs
or Tinkertoys.
I got your ski caps.
What?
No, no, no.
Ski masks. Masks.
Yeah, but the guy said
that these were
the warmest ever made.
With pompoms?
You serious?
You're such an idiot.
I need a mask.
It has to cover your face.
Josh, let's say
we get the money
and make it outside,
then what?
Slide is the only one
with no connection
to The Tower.
So he's agreed
to hold the money
for a week.
Are you crazy?
You're gonna give
this guy $20 million?
He's a crook!
What you say?
Say it again.
I didn't hear shit.
- Speak into the microphone!
- Hey! Hey!
Why don't you
say it again, punk?
Come on, Slide, no guns.
You running
things now, huh?
Man in the suit got
it all figured out?
No, man in the suit
doesn't have it
all figured out,
but man with the gun
needs to understand
what man in the suit
is trying to accomplish
here, all right?
Why you talking like that?
You were talking like that!
Why can't I talk like that?
What you think,
this is a joke, Josh?
We gonna just walk in there
and roll this dude
for $20 million
without a fight?
Look, no guns.
End of story,
all right?
What if we run into
some shit in there
we don't expect?
Trust me,
there won't be
any surprises.
It's the FBI lady
and two cops.
Shit! We haven't
done anything yet.
We're plotters.
We've plotted.
That's a crime, right?
Is that a crime?
Everybody, just relax.
You relax!
I'm out on bail.
I'm gonna go
in the closet.
I'm coming with you.
Guys, it's okay,
I think she's here
for me.
Go find
your own spot.
Hey, Agent Denham,
what a surprise.
What's with the police?
Josh, Arthur Shaw
is gonna walk.
What?
The judge is
gonna dismiss the case
next week at his hearing.
They're acting
like he's untouchable.
That's it? He just
gets away with it?
That's not it.
He's threatening
to press charges
against you.
He wants you to
answer for the Ferrari.
So they're here
to arrest me?
He says he'll
drop the whole thing
if you apologize.
A sincere apology,
that's what Shaw wants.
And if I don't do it?
Then these gentlemen
will read you your rights.
You know what's considered
the greatest move in
the history of chess, Josh?
A man named
Frank James Marshall
was losing to a man
named Levitsky in 1912,
world championship
in Helsinki.
And it looked like
Marshall had no chance
until he moved 23 queen G-3.
He deliberately
sacrificed his queen
and the move
was so shocking
and surprising
that Levitsky
never got over it.
He lost the game
two moves later.
And the move became known
in the annals of chess
as the "Marshall swindle."
I'm a very good
chess player,
but I'm no swindler.
What you did to my Ferrari
was the move of a small man.
But now it's my move,
and I'm not sure how
I want to play this.
All I'd like
to say, Mr. Shaw,
is someday
I'm gonna find a way
to make things right.
I don't care
what I have to do,
I will find
a way to pay you back
for everything
that has been done.
Good, because I know
how difficult it
must be for you
to lose a service job
like this at your age.
And one day when all
this is ancient history,
I hope you can come back,
maybe not as a building
manager at first,
but somewhere where
you can start over,
earn our trust.
A doorman,
for instance.
Now go home
and practice
your chess game.
I'll study
the "Marshall swindle,"
sir.
Anybody can sacrifice
their queen, Josh.
The real trick is
getting away with it.
Thanks for the ride.
Any time.
Oh, God, wait a minute,
before you go,
this is for you.
It's a present.
It's the footage of you
beating the shit
out of Shaw's car.
I took it from
the security camera
in his apartment.
You committed
larceny for me?
Let's just say,
I misplaced three
minutes of footage.
Thank you.
I'm touched.
You're welcome.
Okay.
Are you working
on Saturday night?
I'm always working.
Call in sick.
You're asking
an FBI agent to lie?
I'm asking an FBI
agent to dinner.
I'll see you
Saturday night.
Good.
What the hell is that
in your hand?
It's a present.
She gave you
a present?
I don't know
about the other guys,
but I don't want you
seeing the federal agent
anymore.
I'm not seeing her
until Saturday night.
Oh, my God!
He's dating her.
Relax, my social life
and my criminal life
are totally separate.
They're not separate
if you're dating
the FBI agent who
busted Arthur Shaw!
Shouldn't we be
avoiding law enforcement?
I never saw
an episode of Matlock
where the criminal
banged Matlock!
Well, it don't matter.
Is this the safe?
Yeah.
Then we have a really
serious problem.
You saying
you can't open it?
No, I'm saying
I never worked on
a safe like this before.
I usually break
into strongboxes.
You never said
it was a real safe
made out of steel.
We're going after
$20 million.
What did you think
it would be? Wood?
What kind of thief
can't open a safe?
Well, generally
I rob balconies.
Balconies?
Like a cat burglar?
That way I never get
charged with breaking
and entering.
And I never steal
nothing over $1,000,
because in New York
that shit is a felony.
What do you get?
Like potted plants?
No, bitch!
I don't be stealing
no potted plants!
I steal mostly
satellite dishes.
I got a friend of mine
who be hooking up
illegal DirecTV.
Hey, can your friend
hook me up?
No!
This is a bunch
of horseshit.
Your thief isn't
even a thief.
Hang on a sec.
You can figure
this out, right?
No, I can't
figure this out.
I'm serious.
You have to find
a actual safe-cracker.
Where am I gonna
find a safe-cracker?
I don't know.
You have to start
thinking outside the box.
Shit, you got to find
somebody with some
safe-cracking history. Think!
So, Odessa,
I think we should address
the elephant in the room.
What the hell
you just call me?
No, no.
I'm talking about
the anger you have for me.
How you blame me for
losing the pension,
which is the last thing
I ever wanted to happen.
I know you're
a good man, Mr. K,
even though you
ruined my life.
Which is why
I invited you here.
When I hired you,
I made a note that
you worked for your
father in Kingston.
He was a locksmith.
Yes, the best in Jamaica.
Uh-huh.
Did he teach you
how to open locks
and doors and
things like that?
There ain't no lock
I can't get by, Mr. K.
I was just wondering,
do you think you
could open this thing?
That safe has
a six-number wheel pack
with a double-action fence.
Very tricky spindle.
Probably take me
15 minutes to open.
Fifteen minutes?
Could you show us?
What's in it for me?
2:42,
Lester at his post.
Couple of NYPD officers
at the falafel cart.
Wait a second.
That's Charlie.
What's Charlie doing here?
Yeah, why is Charlie
going into The Tower?
What did you do?
I went to talk to Mr. Simon.
He called me,
said he had a job for me.
He wants me to be
the building manager.
He asked you to be
the building manager?
Yeah, he offered me
your job, so I took it.
That's ridiculous!
You're not qualified.
But it's not ridiculous
for you to rob $20 million?
I can't believe
how irresponsible
you're being!
You really think
that you're gonna
just stroll in there
like Robin Hood
and his band
of merry doormen
and outsmart the guys
with ear pieces and guns?
Why is that so hard
for you to believe, huh?
Why can't you just be
my skinny Friar Tuck?
Come on!
Who's Friar Tuck?
Friar Tuck is the guy
who helps Robin Hood!
I can't do this, Josh.
You put one foot
inside The Tower,
I'm gonna call in a Code Blue.
It's black.
It's Code Black!
You call it black,
I call it blue.
Maybe I made up new codes,
because I'm in charge
of The Tower now.
I'm warning you, Josh,
come near, it's a
Code Blue-Black.
First thing you do,
you have to find
the entry point.
You have to use
your fingers when you
find the entry point.
It's all in the touch.
You married?
Say what?
No, I ain't married.
What's up?
Just taking a poll.
Taking a poll?
I'll take your poll.
Why did you
call me here?
I got a call
two hours ago
from Judge Hollingsworth's
clerk.
They're moving
Arthur's court date
up to Thanksgiving.
Thanksgiving?
The judge wants to avoid
a media circus on this,
let him walk as
quietly as possible.
It's an act of contrition.
By the way,
Agent Denham,
I'll be pressing
charges against Josh
and all his accomplices
the moment
I step out of court.
Come on,
he did what you asked,
he apologized.
It's time everyone
paid for their mistakes.
I agree.
Hello.
There's something
that you need to know.
They moved Shaw's court date
up to Thursday,
and he's coming for you.
You'll be in jail
by the weekend.
That really messes up
our plans, doesn't it?
Josh, you need to
get yourself a lawyer.
Take care.
Great news,
it worked.
We're good
for Thanksgiving.
My sister will be
taking the Q train
to my uncle's
house in Brighton.
She cooks for him
every year.
How am I gonna know
what she looks like?
Here.
Got it.
Okay.
"I know some of you
believe I'm the reason
"Paul McCartney didn't
buy an apartment here
in 2008.
"Maybe I did get
a little confused
"about the meaning
of the word 'wanker.'
"Maybe you heard about
the Mrs. Jin incident.
"I know that I'm
not Josh Kovaks.
"But today
I am your leader.
"And today is Thanksgiving,
the toughest day of
the year for The Tower.
"Forty-three parties,
close to 500 guests,
30 caterers,
"all of Garage 2
blocked until 4:00.
"Today, you might say,
is our Super Bowl.
we will not lose."
Booyah.
The start of
Macy's Thanksgiving Day parade
is just moments away.
Three million people
will line the streets
of this city.
Fifty million more
will watch from homes
all across the country
and around the globe.
When the parade begins,
all eyes turn to the sky
as the largest
balloons in the world
soar above this city.
It's a sight that
brings out the child
in all of us.
Hey, Josh,
here's your sister's phone.
Great.
She's really hot,
by the way.
Watch your head,
Shaw 先生
Where's Slide?
He's supposed
to be here.
They're on the move.
Wait a sec.
- Oh, God.
- What?
What is it?
It's Slide.
Is he coming up here?
- Shit!
- What is he doing?
He's wearing my suit.
He stole my suit.
He's heading
for The Tower.
Well, that's not the plan.
How do you forget a plan?
Didn't he write it down?
He didn't forget it.
All that time he
spent with Odessa,
he thinks he
can open the safe.
I don't understand.
He's going for the money.
Didn't I tell you
he would screw us?
What are we gonna do?
We stick to the plan.
We go on Snoopy.
Holy shit!
You guys are not
gonna believe this.
That girl that
moved into 4811?
She's in French
Playboy this month.
And in French Playboy,
they're even more naked.
Mrs. Goshen is looking
for a Turkish loose tea,
an orange pekoe
or mint melody.
Well, just send her
an assortment, Rose.
"I'm at Lenox Hospital,
my water broke."
It's happening.
Rose, cover for me.
I'm having a baby.
I'm having a baby!
Excuse me.
I'm having a baby.
Guys, check it out.
Snoopy.
I like Snoopy.
Yeah, it's Snoopy.
- Snoopy!
It's Huang's birthday!
Everybody come and sing.
Ron, Manuel,
come and sing.
Come on, everybody.
Everybody come on,
come on now.
Everybody come on now.
So what happened
to Mr. Larkin?
We had to fire Mr. Larkin.
He was involved
with some illicit
sexual behavior
that we at Chase Manhattan
just will not tolerate.
If you wanna wear
a black leather hood
and whip your own ass,
work at Bank of America.
So you'll be taking
over his account,
Mr. Davis?
Yes, I will.
Working holidays?
We've been very
patient with you
with regard to
the Fitzhugh foreclosure,
but the bank is ready to sell.
And we'd like to
personally offer you
a finder's fee
if we can move
the remodel along.
A finder's fee?
Mmm.
We just started
demolishing
the apartment.
The place is gonna
look like new.
It's going to be
one of the finest
units of the building.
I'd love to see it.
Can I see it?
Here you go.
There you go.
Well, looks like
the staff is having
a little party.
We were supposed to
be in that elevator.
Come on.
We have to go up.
Let's go.
All the way
to the top?
So, as you'll see,
this entire apartment
is being redone.
All new appliances.
Floor-to-ceiling windows.
Hardwood floors.
Oh, hardwood floors.
That's nice.
Tell me,
are you gonna do
the closets over?
Yes, right this way.
Oh, yes. This way.
This is the master
bedroom closet.
It'll have new
sliding racks.
And what beautiful doors.
Are these doors
made of mahogany?
- Mr. Davis?
Excuse me, Mr. Davis.
I'm locked in the closet.
Hello?
Sorry, no cleaning now.
It's okay,
I'll come back.
Do you want some cake?
We're celebrating
a birthday downstairs.
No, thank you.
It's amazing cake,
are you sure?
I'm allergic to chocolate.
I break out in hives.
I can't touch it.
Bumbaclot!
You should have
tried the cake, man.
Odessa,
did he take the cake?
He's allergic to chocolate.
I had to beat him.
Oh, shit.
The maid has gone rogue!
Put him in the chair.
Very spacious.
Got it! Come on.
Yeah.
This is incredible.
I have to hand it
to you, Mr. Kovaks,
you were right.
Move away
from the safe.
I ain't gonna
say it again.
Back up!
Are you serious?
What are you doing?
Hey, Josh, I'm a thief.
I keep telling you
I'm a thief, but you
don't want to believe it.
I know exactly what I am.
You're the one
that's confused.
Now back up
before I pop a cap
in your ass.
No.
No?
Yeah, no.
Look at my face.
You see how serious I am.
I'm pretty serious, too.
Are you ready
to die, bitch?
That's my suit.
Yeah, I got on your
suit and your drawers
and socks, too! So what?
I want my suit back.
I will blow your face
clean off your face!
Now, back up!
You think I'm gonna
let this shit get away?
You don't
have a choice.
I brought my own gun.
Now put your shit down,
nice and slow.
You mess with me,
you're a dead man.
Now drop it!
Okay, all right,
all right, all right.
I'm putting it down
right now.
Take it easy.
On the ground,
you punk-ass bitch!
Bitch, on the ground!
We had a plan!
Take it easy.
Fitz, calm down.
Come on now. Shit!
Fitz, take it easy.
Be cool with the gun, man.
Okay. All right.
Relax.
I'm relaxed,
you relax!
You sissy... You bitch!
Ladies and gentlemen,
America's queen of comedy,
Joan Rivers.
And here's Kanye West.
Charlie,
what are you doing back?
Rose, please.
I feel like my
head's gonna fall off.
I raced over to the hospital,
she's not there.
I can't find her.
I get into
an argument
with 15 doctors.
I said, "Where's
my wife?" They said,
"Your wife's not here."
I called my Uncle
Marty in Brighton.
I say,
"You got to
get over here.
"She's not here.
Nobody can find her."
He said,
"What do you mean
no one can find her?
"She's in the television room,
watching television."
I said, "Are you kidding me?
Put her on the telephone."
He puts her
on the telephone.
I said, "What are you doing?
Your water didn't break?"
"No." "Your vagina's
not dilated?" "No."
I said,
"Why did you send
me a text message?"
She says, "I didn't
send you a text message.
I can't find my phone!"
Have you seen Josh?
Manuel,
will you show me
the penthouse hallway?
These FBI guys
are always falling asleep.
Where is Mr. Simon?
He was showing
Mr. Fitzhugh's old
apartment to some guy.
Manuel, do you think
something strange
is going on?
They cut Miss Piggy
from the parade.
I think that's strange.
Well, it's been
nice meeting you,
Agent Denham.
You know, I'm still trying
to decide if I should
go after your badge.
Either way,
no hard feelings
on my part.
Maybe we could
have dinner sometime,
my treat. Huh?
Can I help you?
We have a meeting
with Judge Hollingsworth.
Judge Hollingsworth
is down in D.C.
He goes down every year
to spend the holiday
with his daughter.
Are you sure?
There's no one
here today, ma'am.
It's Thanksgiving.
What the hell
is going on?
Back in the car.
Wait, no.
Wait a second.
Back in the car.
Wait a minute!
Three, four, five,
six, seven, eight.
You open it, Mr. K.
Wow.
Oh, my God.
This can't be real.
Empty! After all
this shit, it's empty.
Man, what kind of...
Give me my gun back.
This is over.
Give me my gun...
I might need it
to get out of here.
I'm not giving it to you.
Stop bullshitting
and give me the gun.
No! I don't want to.
Give me the goddamn gun!
Fitz, give him the gun!
Give him the gun!
Guys. Guys!
What the hell is
wrong with you, man?
You gonna kill
somebody in here!
- Sorry.
- What the hell, man?
Give me that crowbar.
- What?
- Did you find something?
What is that?
Gold.
- Real gold?
- Holy shit.
The hood is solid gold.
Do you have any idea
what that's worth?
It's not just the hood.
It's the whole car.
This is where
he hid the money.
This car must
weigh 2,000 pounds.
Sixteen ounces to a pound,
that's 32,000 ounces.
The current price of
gold is $1,872 per ounce.
Josh, it's about
45 million.
- Jesus!
- $45 million?
Give or take 10 million.
Give me that crow bar.
I am going to break
a chunk off this bitch.
Are we going
to chop it up?
How we gonna do that?
Why don't we take
the whole thing?
What?
What are we gonna do?
Roll it out the front door?
It's not gonna fit.
It is too big.
It won't go
through the door.
Man.
And the doors in
Fitzhugh's apartment
are torn out.
Too bad it is
six floors down.
Shit!
How much you say
it weighs?
It has to be green,
because green means go.
It's moving.
This is crazy.
Josh, this is really crazy.
Okay, all right.
- Got it?
- Yeah.
All right.
Hey, do you know
of any reason
somebody would
want you out of your
penthouse right now?
No.
Mr. Shaw, I think
you're being robbed.
This is a bad idea.
Really? Which part?
The part where
you screw us over
and try to take
everything for yourself?
Even when you were
six you couldn't share.
Maybe I just
didn't want to share
with your silly
seizure-having ass.
All right,
you know what?
That's it!
I don't want you
talking to me for
the rest of the robbery.
Okay, take it up.
All right.
All right, lower it.
- A little more.
Okay, stop!
Grab it, Fitz!
You have to reach
out and pull it in.
I really don't
want to do that.
I wanna go home now.
Home to my old life.
Do you have any idea
how happy I used to be?
My wife and I flew
first class to Greece.
We swam naked.
We ate lamb.
Stop acting
like a bitch
and pull that shit in!
He's freaking out.
We have to get down there.
Shit.
What are you doing?
That's it, we popped.
We are not popped.
What are you doing?
I'm gonna shoot
this guy in the foot
when he comes in
and you are gonna slam
the door in his face.
No, that's a bad idea.
You shoot the FBI
agent in his foot,
he is gonna come in here
and he is gonna shoot
a nigger in his ass.
It's over.
All right, great.
You give up then.
I'm out of here.
Hey!
I can do it.
I'm no bitch.
Yeah.
Okay...
I can do it.
It's kind of like sailing.
Keep moving!
Easy! Easy! Easy! Easy!
I'm not going out there.
I got it!
Oh, no.
Yo, we got a dangler!
Help me!
Fitzhugh is dangling!
- Shit!
- Fitz!
Help!
I'm gonna fall!
Josh, help me!
I don't want to die.
There's a rope.
Grab the rope!
I can't!
Listen to me.
No!
Take your hand off the car
and grab the rope!
It's your only chance!
Yeah! Reach out!
It's too far!
No, it's not!
I got you. I got you.
I got you. Come on.
What are you doing, man?
We're stealing the car.
FBI, you got to
let us through.
Can't. The parade
is coming right at us
for another half hour.
You're gonna have to
go around the entire park.
I'm sorry.
- Holy shit!
- Whoa!
Josh.
Fitzhugh!
What's happening?
Are you okay?
Come in. Fitzhugh!
Dev'Reaux.
Charlie?
Where are you?
The roof!
We need to swing
the car over to the window.
Dev'Reaux,
I'm gonna try
and reel the car in,
but I'm gonna
need your help.
I'm starting to
get kind of queasy.
Fitzhugh, get the rope.
We're gonna hook it.
I'm gonna call Ralph.
What?
I'm getting
ready to call Ralph.
Who's Ralph?
Pull!
Hi, guys.
God damn it, Josh.
You realize what
you have done to me?
You have ruined my life.
Do you understand
that I'm a part
of this now?
And for what?
So you could
steal a car?
Yeah, worth 45 million,
made out of gold.
Gold?
It's worth 45 million?
Give or take 10 million.
All right,
come on. Let's push it
into the elevator.
I don't think
it's gonna fit.
No, it won't fit
in the elevator.
But it doesn't have to.
I'm stopping the elevator
right under you guys.
Okay. So what do we do
when we get it downstairs?
We'll think of something.
Check the glove box.
Keys have to be
here somewhere.
I don't see any keys.
Nothing.
Holy shit!
Josh.
Can you take Lucy
on a walk for me?
My feet are swollen,
and there's a goddamn parade.
You know, now is
not a great time,
Mrs. Cronan.
Charlie,
give her one of those
liver treats that you
keep on your desk.
Yes, ma'am.
Thank you.
Agent Claire Denham
requesting backup
at The Tower on
Central Park West.
Okay.
All right.
On three.
One, two, three.
Come on.
Easy, easy, easy!
Okay, it's stable.
That wasn't so bad.
Whoa!
What's happening?
Why are we moving?
It's security!
They're overriding me!
It's the lobby.
Shh!
Fitz. Take her!
Take Lucy! Here.
What? What?
Okay. I got her.
No, no. No!
Stop, stop, stop, stop!
I think they're gone.
We need to get out
of here right now.
Slide.
Yeah.
We got to use the truck.
Where are the keys?
Under the sun visor.
You leave the keys?
In New York?
It's a stolen car.
You brought
a stolen car
to a robbery?
Lester,
you still there?
Yeah, I'm here.
I'm holding four cabs
at the north door.
Slight change of plan.
There's a white truck parked
on 60th and Broadway,
keys on the visor.
You got to back it
up to the elevator.
I'm on my way.
Mr. Shaw, tell me
about this safe.
It's empty.
Doesn't matter if
it's empty or full.
A hidden safe
was never mentioned
in the inventory
of your apartment.
You neglected
to inform us,
which is a violation
of your parole,
therefore...
Where is my car?
Where is my goddamn car?
I hereby remand you
to federal custody
until your real court date.
You just forfeited
$10 million.
You think I care
about $10 million?
if I spend a few
nights in jail?
We both know I'm
going to be out
by the weekend.
But you let that car
leave this building
and I promise you
won't get off so easy.
Take him away.
Lock it down.
This is Agent Huggins.
Lock down the building.
Show me the garage.
Okay. Yes, ma'am.
They got the car.
Come on! Come on!
There they are!
Here we go, baby.
Move out of the way.
Go. Go.
Get out of the way!
Careful. Careful.
Jesus Christ!
Freeze! Do not move!
Open it.
Son of a bitch!
It's a diversion.
Lester,
they are gonna get hurt.
There is no way out of this.
I don't know what
you are talking about.
All I did is steal a truck
and try to commit suicide.
- Mr. Fitzhugh? FBI.
- You're under arrest, sir.
Oh.
Please put your hands
behind your back.
Miss Montero, FBI,
you're under arrest.
Charlie Gibbs, FBI,
You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say,
can and will be
used against you
in a court of law.
You have the right
to an attorney.
Mr. Dev'Reaux, FBI.
Show me your hands.
You're under arrest.
Show me your hands, Josh.
It was smart.
Thanksgiving, the parade,
changing the court date,
using Lester
as a diversion,
lying to me.
We have reservations
Saturday night at six
different restaurants.
I'll give you the names
if you wanna check.
That's okay,
I trust you.
Where is my car?
Do you mean
the car made of gold?
Gold melted down
from the money you stole?
I haven't seen it.
They'll find it.
And when they do,
my friends on the bench
will take no pity on you.
They'll make sure
you go away for
a very long time.
See, you people
are working stiffs,
clock punchers.
Easily replaced
and erased.
And just know that
while you are all
sitting in jail,
I'll be right up
there in the penthouse
of The Tower,
doing what I do best.
We may be going to
jail for a few years,
but you, you're going
for the rest of your life.
How'd you figure that?
I found your ledger.
You know,
the one that
you stuck
in the owner's manual
of your Ferrari.
Tsk, tsk, tsk.
I'm guessing you
don't really care
about the car.
You could care less
about 45 million,
but I bet you want
that ledger back.
Am I right?
What do you
think you're doing?
Sacrificing my queen.
Okay, you and I
are gonna make
a deal, Josh.
A deal that will
make you and your
friends very wealthy.
Do you think
that car has value?
Multiply it by 10.
In cash.
Dev'Reaux, will you
please remind Mr. Shaw?
I'm very sorry, Mr. Shaw,
but we don't accept
tips at The Tower.
Checkmate.
Hello!
We've got FBI
agents and police
all over the city.
We know about
your friend Slide
from Astoria.
Your little trick
with Lester may have
gotten the car
out of the building,
but it's just
a matter of time
before we find it.
Who is this?
Director Mazin.
I am Mr. Kovaks' attorney,
Miss lovenko.
I will be representing
all the defendants
in this case.
And you're licensed
to practice in the state
of New York?
I passed the bar
three days ago.
I'd like to request
the immediate release
of all the defendants.
On what grounds?
These are Mr. Shaw's
hand-written notes
detailing his
fraudulent business
practices.
There are names, dates,
account numbers.
My guess is you'll
find enough evidence
in there
to put him away
for a very long time.
But this only happens
if my clients walk.
You've been a lawyer
for less than a week
and you're trying
to bribe the United
States government?
Sharks are born
swimming, sir.
I'll let everyone
walk but Kovaks.
As a first-time offender,
he'll probably get
two years for the car.
Best I can do.
Nobody else
will be charged?
New evidence in
the Arthur Shaw trial
has prompted a new plea
from the accused swindler.
Sources are now
confirming that Mr. Shaw
will enter
a guilty plea next week.
Are we gonna
do this or what?
Mmm-hmm.
Hallelujah!
Welcome to
the penthouse,
Shaw 先生
Look who's coming now.
Wait until
I get a hold of
your wrinkled ass.
He looks good!
Are you Rose Demato?
Yes.
Sign right here, please.
All right, thanks.
It's a gold wheel!
支持我们，欢迎购买VIP移除所有广告，具体：www.OpenSubtitles.org